# VICTOR OSVALDO ONOFRE GONZALEZ

Physicist | Graduate Student at the Center of Nanoscience and Nanotechnology (CNyN) of the National Autonomous University of México (UNAM)

@ vonofre68@gmail.com victor-onofre-a9b1371a7 **3** 664-243-46-56 Ensenada, Baja California, Mexico

medium.com/@vonofre68

**梦** @VicOnofre1

victor-onofre

# **SUMMARY**

I'm currently waiting for the final revisions of my thesis for my master's degree in physics in the area of Quantum Biology. I worked with concepts of quantum information and simulations of open quantum systems in Python. I'm interested in applying quantum algorithms to solve real-world problems.

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science - MS, Physics

Center of Nanoscience and Nanotechnology (CNyN) of the National Autonomous University of México (UNAM)

August 2018 - Expected April 2021

- Ensenada, Baja California, Mexico
- · Thesis: Discord-type quantum correlations in the radical pair mechanism for magnetoreception in birds
- Simulations of the dynamics of open quantum systems in python using the QuTip library
- Research in quantum biology
- Worked with discord-type quantum correlations. Example: 😯 victor-onofre/Quantum\_correlations\_of\_the\_Werner\_State
- Worked with quantum algorithms. 🜍 victor-onofre/Quantum Algorithms
- Adviser: Dr. Fernando Rojas Iñiguez in PHD Fernando Rojas
- @ frojas371@gmail.com
- Highlight courses: Quantum Mechanics I and II, Statistical mechanics, Quantum Correlations and Quantum Information

Bachelor's degree, Physics

Autonomous University of Baja California

**August 2012 - March 2018** 

- Ensenada, Baja California, Mexico
- Thesis: Numerical simulation of the harmonic oscillator in stochastic electrodynamics
- Simulations in Fortran 90 of systems in stochastic electrodynamics
- Highlight project: Simulation of the spin in the Stern-Gerlach experiment using a quantum automaton. Poster of the project in Spanish (Click here)

# **EXPERIENCE**

iQuHACK (interdisciplinary Quantum HACKathon) 2021 | Team won in the hybrid division 

**a** January 30 -31, 2021

E-Learning

• We worked on solving the Knapsack problem with gate-based game running on lonQ hardware and annealing-based Discrete Quadratic Model (DQM) method running on D-Wave hardware. Link to the project: ? iQuHACK/2021\_Hybrid-Daemons

Qubit by Qubit | Development of content for a textbook

The Coding School

December 2020 - Ongoing

E-Learning

• Development of curriculum materials, course materials, homework, practice sets and content for the textbook: Introduction to Quantum Computing for High School Students. 

qubitbyqubit.org

Co-Founder of Quantum Hispano | Coordinator of the scientific outreach team **Quantum Computing** 

September 2020 - Ongoing

E-Learning

• Community of people interested in quantum computing for a Spanish-speaking audience. 

quantumhispano.org

- Coordinate part of the organization of work teams with members from Peru, Ecuador, Paraguay, Colombia and Mexico using internet communication tools.
- Create content to inform, educate, and raise awareness of quantum computing.

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Most experienced with Python (Pandas, SciPy, QuTip, Qiskit, Scikit-Learn, keras, TensorFlow)
- Worked with MATLAB, Mathematica, Fortran 90, and C/C++ (MPI)

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Quantum Information
- Quantum Biology
- Finance
- Data Science
- Machine Learning
- Chemistry

## TECHNICAL TOOLS

- LaTeX
- OriginLab
- Microsoft Office
- Operating systems: Windows and Linux

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (Native) English (Full Professional Proficiency)



# PERSONAL PROJECTS

# Violence and local business in the city of Tijuana

#### **Python project**

- ▼ Final report (Click here)
- Analysis of the most common business in the more violent neighborhoods in the city of Tijuana
- Data acquisition and cleaning of large data in pandas library
- Use of location data from the API of Foursquare
- Use of the Folium library to create maps of geospatial data

#### **Posters**

#### For Quantum Hispano and Film-club CNyN

- Portfolio (Click here)
- Use of Adobe Spark, canva, GIMP and lucidchart tools.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **IBM Data Science Specialization**

#### Coursera

April 2020 - No Expiration Date

E-Learning

- Credential ID: WANKVTDUMF2G Credential URL (Click here)
- In 9 courses, I applied Data Science methodology Worked with Jupyter notebooks Accessed relational databases using SQL and Python Used Python libraries to generate data visualizations **Performed data analysis using Pandas** Constructed and evaluated Machine Learning (ML) models using Scikit-learn and SciPy and applied data science and ML techniques to real location data sets.

#### **IBM AI Engineering Specialization**

#### Coursera

**i** July 2020 - No Expiration Date

E-Learning

- Credential ID: 562XFPRHV6G9 Credential URL (Click here)
- In 6 courses, I applied Machine Learning (ML) techniques such as regression, classification, clustering, and recommender systems
  and became able to scale ML on Big Data using Apache Spark Learned to build, test and deploy Deep Learning models using
  libraries such as Keras, PyTorch, and Tensorflow Finished several ML and Deep Learning projects.

#### Perform Sentiment Analysis with Scikit-Learn

#### Coursera

July 2020 - No Expiration Date

E-Learning

- Credential ID: YDNDAZRXKSBS Credential URL (Click here)
- I cleaned and pre-processed text data Builded and employed a logistic regression classifier using Scikit-Learn Performed feature extraction with The Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK) Tuned model hyperparameters and evaluated model accuracy.

# WORKSHOPS AND SCHOOLS

#### Qiskit Global Summer School

#### Hosted virtually

**J**uly 20-31, 2020

E-Learning

Qiskit is an open-source framework for working with quantum computers at the level of circuits, pulses, and algorithms. The Qiskit
Global Summer School was hosted virtually within two weeks of intense lectures and labs. The curriculum consisted of 3 hour long
lectures every day, accompanied by a lab, starting with the definition of Qubits and quantum states, and ending with
Superconducting Qubits and Quantum Chemistry.

#### QuEBS 2019: Workshop on Quantum Effects in Biological Systems

#### **Poster Presentation**

Ctober 27-31, 2019

Puebla, Mexico

- In this annual workshop, the interplay between quantum coherence and environmental effects in both driven and undriven biomolecular systems were explored.
- Exposition of the project: Susceptibility of the quantum fisher information as a measure of the non-stationary multipartite entanglement in the linear response regime in the radical pair mechanism of the avian compass model.
- Poster of the project (Click here)

### IV Symposium of Nanosciences and Nanomaterials

#### **Poster Presentation**

**23-27 April 2018** 

- Ensenada, Baja California, Mexico
- The main purpose of this symposium is to bring together experimental and theoretical researchers in the fields of nanoscience and nanotechnology and discuss on current developments in these areas.
- Exposition of the project: Simulation of the harmonic oscillator in stochastic electrodynamics.

#### Quantum Info - Guanajuato 2017

#### A Workshop dedicated to the quantum information technologies

**1**-6 November 2017

Guanajuato, Gto, Mexico

#### Lectures:

- High-dimensional quantum cryptography with Structured Photons by Ebrahim Karimi (University of Ottawa)
- Quantum Memories and QKD by Edén Figueroa (Stony Brook University)
- Introduction to discrete variable Quantum Key Distribution by Guisepe Vallone (University of Padova)
- Quantum State Estimation and applications in Metrology by Luis Snchez-Soto (Complutense University of Madrid)
- Introduction to Practical QKD: Implementation and security by Shihan Sajeed (University of Waterloo)

# X Annual Meeting of the Quantum Information Division of the Mexican Society of Physics

#### **Poster Presentation**

**27-29 September 2017** 

- San Luis Potosi, San Luis Potosi, Mexico
- Exposition of the project: Simulation of the spin in the Stern-Gerlach experiment using a quantum automaton.
- Poster of the project in Spanish (Click here)